Guide to the Severinghaus family papers, 1922-1994
Severinghaus family papers, 1922-1994
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
Severinghaus family papers, 1922-1994
4240
Severinghaus family.
33 cubic ft.
Subject files, correspondence, photographs, movie films, audiotapes, ephemera.
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
Subject files, correspondence, photographs, movie films, audiotapes, ephemera, and other material pertaining to the personal life and professional career of Leslie Severinghaus and his family (particularly his wife Emmavail Luce Severinghaus). Chief topics include the Peking Union Medical College, travel and work in China, education, the Haverford School in Pennsylvania, and Wellesley College.
BIOGRAPHICAL NOTE
Leslie Richard Severinghaus was born in 1899, the son of Charles E. and Anna Edward Severinghaus. After graduating from Cornell University in 1921, he taught English at the Peking Union Medical College in Peking, China and later served as head of the English Department and Headmaster of the Haverford School. He was a member of the Cornell University Board of Trustees. While in Peking, Leslie Severinghaus met and married Emmavail Luce who had returned to China after her 1922 graduation from Wellesley College to serve as a foreign secretary in the YWCA.
COLLECTION DESCRIPTION
Subject files, correspondence, photographs, movie films, audiotapes, ephemera, and other material pertaining to the personal life and professional career of Leslie Severinghaus and his family (particularly his wife Emmavail Luce Severinghaus). Chief topics include the Peking Union Medical College, travel and work in China, education, the Haverford School in Pennsylvania, and Wellesley College.
Additional material includes letters written from China, 1922-1927; photographs and photograph albums; other files; 1980 compilation of TIME magazine articles on the Philippines, 1970-1980; typescript report "Common Sense and the Constitution,"1982, on separation of church and state; reprint about college admissions policies, 1963; article on the Peking Union Medical College, 1982; and "Changing Times and Cornell's Presidency," a report to the Board of Trustees, 1961. Also, photographs taken at Cornell University, 1986; videotape made for the celebration of the donation of the Leslie R. Severinghaus Reading Room; and items from the dedication of the Reading Room, 1992. Also, program for memorial service, and hymns. Also, nine framed items, including posters, watercolor portrait of Severinghaus, prints, and sketches and a scrapbook concerning the Severinghaus Reading Room in Kroch Library.
SUBJECTS
Names:
Severinghaus family.; Severinghaus, Leslie R., 1899-; Severinghaus, Emmavail Luce.; Severinghaus, Sheldon Root.; Chung-kuo hsieh ho i k o ta hsueh.; Chung-kuo hsieh ho i ko ta hsueh.; Cornell University. Board of Trustees.; Haverford School.; Wellesley College.
Subjects:
Time.; Church and state--United States.; Universities and colleges--Admission.
Places:
China--Description.; Philippines--Politics and government.; China--Description.
INFORMATION FOR USERS
SERIES LIST
Series I. Personal
Correspondence
Boxes 1-4
Family Correspondence
Boxes 1, 5, 6, 9, 11
Journal/diaries/memoirs/planners
Boxes 7-15
Additional Personal
Boxes 57-59
Series II. China
Peking Union Medical College (PUMC)
Box 16
American Bureau of Medical Aid for China (ABMAC)
Box 17
American Oral English Program (SLUR)
Box 18
Series III. Schools
Haverford School
Boxes 19, 29
Palmer
Box 20
"Experiment": Green Mountains International Work and Language Camp at Goddard College
Boxes 24, 49, 50
Headmasters Associations
Box 22
Series IV. Cornell
Box 23
Series V. Travel
Boxes 30-33
Series VI. Subject Files
Religion, State, Schools
Boxes 24, 28
Wellesley (Emmavail)
Boxes 24, 26, 27
Speeches/addresses
Boxes 24, 27
Financial
Box 24, 29
Directorships
Box 25
Audubon
Box 29
Newspaper Clippings
Box 28
Hartford Outline
Box 28
Series VII. Visual Material and Ephemera
Photograph Albums
Boxes 26, 34-39
Photographs
Boxes 32, 49-52
Slides
Boxes 40-45, 66-68, 71
Negatives
Boxes 46-48, 53-56
Ephemera
Boxes 62, 65, Map Cases KK20, DD 10
Series VIII. Audio and Audiovisual Materials
Reel tapes
Boxes 60, 69
Cassette tapes
Box 60
Video cassettes
Boxes 69-70
Film
Boxes 60-61 69-71
CONTAINER LIST
- Series I. Personal
  Includes original and transcribed correspondence to and from Leslie Severinghaus and his extended family; original and transcribed journals and diaries of Leslie Severinghaus and the Luce and Severinghaus families' memoirs of Charles E. Severinghaus and Leslie and Emmavail Severinghaus; and the daily planners of Leslie Severinghaus. Family correspondence includes Leslie's extensive collection of correspondence to and from father Charles E. Severinghaus, brother Aura E. Severinghaus, and son Sheldon Root Severinghaus. Additional personal includes Luce and Severinghaus family genealogies, and address book, memorial service material, and books.
  - Correspondence
    - H. W. Luce Papers, 1924 (Box 1, Folder 1)
    - Yenching Files, 1929-41 (Box 1, Folder 1)
    - Elizabeth Root and Henry Winters Luce: Congratulatory Correspondence upon Engagement, 1896 (copied/transcribed in 'Discovery') (Box 1, Folder 2)
    - Elizabeth Root Luce, 1940-48 (Box 1, Folder 3)
    - Helen Van Voast - Elizabeth Root Luce Correspondence (Box 1, Folder 4)
    - Correspondence re: H. W. Luce illness, memorial (Box 1, Folder 5)
    - Elizabeth Luce Correspondence re. Religion (Box 1, Folder 6)
    - Henry and Elizabeth Luce Correspondence (Box 1, Folder 7)
    - Miscellaneous Correspondence (fragments/no dates) (Box 1, Folder 8)
    - Early Miscellaneous (Box 1, Folder 9)
    - Severinghaus Correspondence (family) (Box 1, Folder 10)
    - Mrs. Richard Lawrence (letters, postcards, photos) (Box 1, Folder 11)
    - Children's Correspondence (Box 1, Folder 12-13)
    - Children's Artwork (Box 1, Folder 14)
    - Letters from Sheldon, undergraduate student at Cornell, 1959-? (Box 1, Folder 15)
    - Correspondence: Sheldon in Pakistan (Box 1, Folder 16)
    - Leslie Severinghaus Letters to Sheldon, 1964-69 (Box 1, Folder 17-19)
    - Additional Emmavail Severinghaus Correspondence, 1920's-? (Box 1, Folder 20)
    - Announcements (Box 1, Folder 21)
    - Charles E. Severinghaus, 1890's (Box 1, Folder 22)
    - To Charles E. Severinghaus, 1940-50 (Box 1, Folder 23)
    - Correspondence: J. G. Schaal and Charles E. Severinghaus, 1940-45 (Box 1, Folder 24)
    - Charles E. Severinghaus Correspondence, 1944 (Box 1, Folder 25)
    - Correspondence concerning Charles E. Severinghaus, 1939-63 (Box 1, Folder 26-28)
    - Charles E. Severinghaus Correspondence, 1945-48 (Box 1, Folder 29)
    - Cornell Undergraduate Correspondence (including papers), 1918-22 (Box 1, Folder 30)
    - Leslie Severinghaus Correspondence, 1920 (Box 1, Folder 31)
    - Leslie Severinghaus Correspondence, 1922 (Box 1, Folder 32)
    - Peking and PUMC - Leslie Severinghaus Correspondence, 1922-27 (Box 1, Folder 33)
    - PUMC - Correspondence (Leslie Severinghaus) (Box 29, Folder 5)
    - Leslie Severinghaus Correspondence, 1923 (Box 1, Folder 34)
    - Leslie Severinghaus Correspondence - Jan.-May, 1923 (Box 1, Folder 35)
    - Correspondence - June-Dec., 1923 (Box 1, Folder 36)
    - Correspondence, 1924 (Box 1, Folder 37)
    - Correspondence, 1925 (Box 1, Folder 38-40)
    - Correspondence, 1926 (Box 1, Folder 41)
    - Correspondence, 1926-27 (Box 1, Folder 42)
    - Correspondence, 1927 (Box 2, Folder 1-2)
    - Letters/daily logs of Emmavail Severinghaus and Leslie Severinghaus regarding return to United States, 1927 (Box 2, Folder 3)
    - Correspondence, 1928 (Box 2, Folder 4)
    - Correspondence, 1929 (Box 2, Folder 5)
    - Correspondence, 1933 (Box 2, Folder 6)
    - Alcohol, 1933 (Box 2, Folder 7)
    - Correspondence, 1934 (Box 2, Folder 8)
    - Correspondence, 1935 (Box 2, Folder 9)
    - Correspondence, 1936 (Box 2, Folder 10)
    - Correspondence, 1937 (Box 2, Folder 11)
    - Correspondence, 1938 (Box 2, Folder 12)
    - Correspondence, 1939 (Box 2, Folder 13)
    - Correspondence, Political, re. China/Japan, 1939 (Box 2, Folder 14)
    - Correspondence, 1940 (Box 2, Folder 15)
    - Peter Martin Lampel, 1939-64 (Box 2, Folder 16)
    - Correspondence, 1941 (Box 2, Folder 17)
    - Correspondence (political, trade with China) with support material, 1941-54 (Box 2, Folder 18)
    - Correspondence, 1942 (Box 2, Folder 19)
    - Correspondence, 1945 (Box 2, Folder 20)
    - Correspondence, 1946 (Box 2, Folder 21)
    - Correspondence, 1947 (Box 2, Folder 22)
    - Correspondence, 1948 (Box 2, Folder 23)
    - Correspondence re: Catholicism and Secularism, 1948, 1960 (Box 2, Folder 24)
    - Correspondence, 1950 (Box 2, Folder 25)
    - Correspondence, 1951 (Box 2, Folder 26)
    - Correspondence, 1952 (Box 2, Folder 27)
    - Correspondence, 1953 (Box 2, Folder 28)
    - Correspondence, 1954 (Box 2, Folder 29)
    - Correspondence, 1955 (Box 2, Folder 30)
    - Correspondence, 1956 (Box 2, Folder 31)
    - Correspondence, 1957 (Box 2, Folder 32)
    - Correspondence, 1958 (Box 2, Folder 33)
    - Correspondence, 1959 (Box 2, Folder 34)
    - Correspondence, 1960-63 (Box 2, Folder 35)
    - Correspondence, 1961 (Box 2, Folder 36)
    - Europe Trip, 1961 (Box 2, Folder 37)
    - ACAC Journal Article: "A Philosophy for College Admissions," 1963-64 (Box 2, Folder 38)
    - Correspondence, 1964 (Box 2, Folder 39)
    - Correspondence, 1965 (Box 2, Folder 40)
    - Leslie Severinghaus to Emmavail Severinghaus (Taiwan trip) 1966 (Box 2, Folder 41)
    - Leslie Severinghaus to Emmavail Severinghaus, Oct. 12-Dec. 1, 1966 (Box 2, Folder 42)
    - Leslie Severinghaus to Emmavail Severinghaus - Coconut Grove/Taiwan, 1966 (Box 2, Folder 43)
    - Emmavail Severinghaus to RLS (Taiwan trip) 1966 (Box 2, Folder 44)
    - Correspondence, 1966-67 (Box 2, Folder 45)
    - Correspondence, 1968 (Box 2, Folder 46)
    - Correspondence, 1969 (Box 2, Folder 47)
    - Henry R. Luce Biography, 1969-72 (Box 2, Folder 48)
    - Correspondence, 1970 (Box 2, Folder 49)
    - Correspondence with Tan Lu-Sheng, 1970-80 (Box 2, Folder 50)
    - Correspondence, 1971 (Box 2, Folder 51)
    - Correspondence, 1972 (Box 2, Folder 52)
    - Correspondence, 1973 (Box 2, Folder 53)
    - Leslie Severinghaus - Theodore Wilder Correspondence (Ornithology), 1973-89 (Box 2, Folder 54)
    - Correspondence, 1974 (Box 2, Folder 55)
    - Correspondence, 1975 (Box 2, Folder 56)
    - Correspondence, 1976 (Box 2, Folder 57)
    - Correspondence, 1977 (Box 2, Folder 58)
    - Correspondence, 1978 (Box 2, Folder 59)
    - Correspondence, 1979 (Box 2, Folder 60)
    - Dingle Family Correspondence, 1970's (Box 2, Folder 61)
    - Correspondence - fragments, 1970's (Box 2, Folder 62)
    - Correspondence, 1980 (Box 2, Folder 63)
    - Correspondence, 1981 (Box 2, Folder 64)
    - Correspondence, 1982 (Box 2, Folder 65)
    - Correspondence, 1983 (Box 2, Folder 66)
    - Correspondence, 1984 (Box 2, Folder 67)
    - Correspondence, 1984 (Box 3, Folder 1)
    - Christmas Correspondence; Emmavail Severinghaus condolences, 1985 (Box 3, Folder 2-3)
    - Condolences - Emmavail's death, 1985 (Box 3, Folder 4)
    - Correspondence, 1985 (Box 3, Folder 5-6)
    - Correspondence, 1986 (Box 3, Folder 7)
    - Leslie Severinghaus visit to Franklin Ave. Methodist Episcopal Church (father was pastor), 1987 (Box 3, Folder 8)
    - Correspondence, 1987 (Box 3, Folder 9)
    - Correspondence, 1988 (Box 3, Folder 10)
    - Palmetto Presbyterian Church Correspondence, 1988-90 (Box 3, Folder 11)
    - Correspondence, 1989 (Box 3, Folder 12)
    - Undated Correspondence, 1980's (Box 3, Folder 13)
    - Correspondence, 1990 (Box 3, Folder 14)
    - Correspondence, 1991 (Box 3, Folder 15)
    - Correspondence, 1992 (Box 3, Folder 16)
    - Correspondence, 1993 (Box 3, Folder 17)
    - Correspondence, 1994 (Box 3, Folder 18)
    - Correspondence - undated/fragments, 1990's (Box 3, Folder 19)
    - Correspondence with Lala Iverson - includes Iverson's manuscript: "Sermon on the Mount," 1989-90 (Box 3, Folder 20)
    - Correspondence to Grandchildren (Box 3, Folder 21)
    - Correspondence from folder titled "Religion," 1986-93 (Box 3, Folder 22)
    - Christmas Newsletters (Box 3, Folder 23)
    - Correspondence - Retirement, 1965 (Box 4, Folder 1-2)
    - Correspondence with J. George Black, 1944-58 (Box 4, Folder 3)
    - Correspondence - Dr. E. M. Wilson, 1939-65 (Box 4, Folder 4)
    - Leslie Severinghaus-Lala Iverson Correspondence, 1993-94 (Box 4, Folder 5)
    - Correspondence, 1964-90 (Box 4, Folder 6)
    - Correspondence - Overseas Students, 1961-65 (Box 4, Folder 7)
    - Congratulatory Correspondence - Headmastership, 1942 (Box 4, Folder 8)
    - Van Pelt Correspondence, 1941-62 (Box 4, Folder 9)
    - Correspondence - G. Dickson Garner, 1943-64 (Box 4, Folder 10)
    - Correspondence - Europe Trip, 1963 (Box 4, Folder 11)
  - Family Correspondence
    - Walter L. Severinghaus Correspondence, 1927 (Box 5, Folder 1)
    - Correspondence to Walter L. Severinghaus, 1940-62 (Box 5, Folder 2)
    - Walter L. Severinghaus Correspondence, 1926-73 (Box 5, Folder 3)
    - Severinghaus Correspondence (Box 5, Folder 4)
    - Early Correspondence: Aura, Esther and Leslie Severinghaus to home (originals with transcriptions) (Box 5, Folder 5-6)
    - Aura E. Severinghaus - assorted correspondence (Box 5, Folder 7)
    - Aura E. Severinghaus Correspondence, 1912-14 (Box 5, Folder 8)
    - Aura E. Severinghaus Correspondence, 1914-16 (Box 5, Folder 9)
    - Aura E. Severinghaus Correspondence, 1913-17 (Box 5, Folder 10)
    - Aura E. Severinghaus Correspondence, 1939-40 (Box 5, Folder 11)
    - Aura E. Severinghaus Correspondence, 1940 (Box 5, Folder 12)
    - Aura E. Severinghaus Correspondence, 1939-40 (Box 5, Folder 13)
    - Aura E. Severinghaus Correspondence, 1940 (Box 5, Folder 14)
    - Aura E. Severinghaus Correspondence (not family), 1912 (Box 5, Folder 15)
    - Aura E. Severinghaus Correspondence (not family), 1914 (Box 5, Folder 16)
    - Aura E. Severinghaus Correspondence (not family), 1915-17 (Box 5, Folder 17)
    - Aura E. Severinghaus Correspondence (not family), 1918 (Box 5, Folder 18)
    - Aura E. Severinghaus Correspondence (not family), 1919-20 (Box 5, Folder 19)
    - Aura E. Severinghaus Correspondence (not family) April 1-Aug. 20, undated, 1920 (Box 5, Folder 20)
    - Aura E. Severinghaus Correspondence (Box 5, Folder 21)
    - Aura E. Severinghaus and Sally Severinghaus Correspondence (Box 5, Folder 22)
    - Aura E. Severinghaus Correspondence, 1918-25 (Box 5, Folder 23)
    - Aura E. Severinghaus Correspondence, 1923-37 (Box 5, Folder 24)
    - Aura E. Severinghaus Correspondence, 1925 (Box 5, Folder 25)
    - Aura E. Severinghaus Correspondence, 1926 (Box 5, Folder 26)
    - Aura E. Severinghaus Correspondence, 1939 (Box 5, Folder 27)
    - Aura E. Severinghaus Correspondence, 1940 (Box 5, Folder 28)
    - Aura E. Severinghaus Correspondence, 1941-76 (Box 5, Folder 29)
    - Charles E. Severinghaus to Aura E. Severinghaus Correspondence, 1941-48 (Box 5, Folder 30)
    - Charles E. Severinghaus to AEA Correspondence, 1945 (Box 5, Folder 31)
    - Aura E. Severinghaus Correspondence to home (Box 5, Folder 32)
    - Aura E. Severinghaus Correspondence, 1925-50 (Box 5, Folder 33)
    - Family Letters to Aura E. Severinghaus, 1918 (Box 5, Folder 34)
    - Aura E. Severinghaus Correspondence to Home, 1917-19 (Box 5, Folder 35)
    - Aura E. Severinghaus - Family Correspondence (Box 5, Folder 36-37)
    - Aura E. Severinghaus - Personal, Financial (Peking) (Box 5, Folder 38)
    - Aura E. Severinghaus - Sarah M. Nay wedding certificate, photos, bride's book, 1923 (Box 5, Folder 39)
    - Aura E. Severinghaus Last Will and Testament, 1974 (Box 5, Folder 40)
    - Henry R. Luce - Early Correspondence (transcribed), p. 21-120 (Box 6, Folder 1)
    - Henry R. Luce - Early Correspondence (transcribed), p. 123-159 (Box 6, Folder 2)
    - Henry R. Luce - Early Correspondence (transcribed), p. 260-409 (Box 6, Folder 3)
    - Henry R. Luce - Early Correspondence (transcribed), p. 410-521, Index (Box 6, Folder 4)
    - Luce Correspondence (transcribed), 1903-1922 (Box 6, Folder 5)
    - Luce Family Correspondence (transcribed) (Box 6, Folder 6-8)
    - Esther Louise Severinghaus Correspondence (transcribed) (Box 6, Folder 9)
    - Charles E. Severinghaus to Leslie Severinghaus Correspondence (transcribed), 1940-46 (Box 6, Folder 10)
    - Severinghaus Family Correspondence (photocopies and transcriptions), 1930's-40's (Box 6, Folder 11)
    - Assorted Family Correspondence - Luce/Severinghaus (photocopied/transcribed) (Box 6, Folder 12)
    - "Chits" between Leslie Severinghaus and Emmavail in courting (transcribed) (Box 6, Folder 13)
    - Leslie Severinghaus Correspondence, Vols. I and II (transcribed), 1922-27 (Box 6, Folder 14-15)
    - Leslie Severinghaus - "The China Letters" (bound/transcribed), 1922-27 (Box 6, Folder 16)
    - Leslie Severinghaus Correspondence to Sheldon Severinghaus (transcribed), 1964-65 (Box 6, Folder 17)
    - Emmavail Severinghaus Correspondence regarding the birth of Sheldon Severinghaus and the move to Buck Lane, Haverford, 1940 (Box 6, Folder 18)
  - Journal/diaries/memoirs/planners
    - Grace Colby Severinghaus - Christmas letter collection, 1932-88 (Box 7, Folder 1)
    - Charles Edwin Elmer Severinghaus Autobiography, 1865-1941 (Box 7, Folder 2)
    - History of the Severinghaus Family by Charles Severinghaus, 1991 (Box 7, Folder 3)
    - Esther Severinghaus funeral service (Box 7, Folder 4)
    - Leslie Severinghaus photographic scrapbook, family history, 1956 (Box 7, Folder 5)
    - H. W. Luce notebook? (Box 7, Folder 6)
    - Emmavail Luce - Wellesley, 1918-22 (Box 7, Folder 7)
    - "Astronomye" English Lit. 8B - Emmavail, 1920 (Box 7, Folder 8)
    - English 308B - "A Comparison" (Emmavail), 1922 (Box 7, Folder 9)
    - English Lit. 308B - "Opinions Concerning Women" (Emmavail), 1922 (Box 7, Folder 10)
    - English Lit. 308 - Browning (Emmavail) (Box 7, Folder 11)
    - Emmavail Luce - Wellesley, History 3F paper, 1922 (Box 7, Folder 12)
    - English Lit. - "Stevenson's Spirit of Adventure" (Emmavail) (Box 7, Folder 13)
    - St. Agnes - English Lit. 308 (Emmavail) (Box 7, Folder 14)
    - English Lit. 308 (Emmavail) (Box 7, Folder 15)
    - Diaries of Emmavail Luce - transcribed, 1913 (Box 7, Folder 16)
    - Emmavail Luce Diary (transcribed), 1917-19 (Box 7, Folder 17)
    - "Forward: two more diaries of Emmavail Luce" - Wellesley, 1919-22 (Box 7, Folder 18)
    - Emmavail Severinghaus - Travel Journals, V. I and II, 1922, 1954 (Box 7, Folder 19)
    - Emmavail Luce Diaries (transcribed), 1920, 1921 (Box 7, Folder 20)
    - Emmavail Luce journal entries - "The Trip to England", 1921 (Box 7, Folder 21)
    - Emmavail Luce - Memoirs - passage to Peking from U.S., 192 (Box 7, Folder 22)
    - Emmavail letters home to friends; diaries, 1922-27 (Box 7, Folder 23)
    - "Popular Education in Tsinanfu" (Emmavail), 1923 (Box 7, Folder 24)
    - YWCA Wellesley in China (Emmavail), 1923-24 (Box 7, Folder 25)
    - Emmavail (Box 7, Folder 26)
    - Leslie Severinghaus - Autobiographical Sequence, 1899-1923 (Box 7, Folder 27)
    - "An Autobiographical Sequence" Vol. II, 1982 (Box 7, Folder 28)
    - Honorary Degrees - Dickinson, Trinity, Pennsylvania, Temple (Box 7, Folder 29)
    - Testimonial Dinner (transcribed), 1978 (Box 7, Folder 30)
    - Testimonial to Leslie Severinghaus, Cornell University Trustees - remarks by Leslie Severinghaus (Box 7, Folder 31)
    - Aura E. Severinghaus - Memorial Service (Box 7, Folder 32)
    - College Expenses (Box 7, Folder 33)
    - Cornell University Undergraduate - Accounts, Grades, etc., 1918-22 (Box 7, Folder 34)
    - Cornell University papers on Wordsworth, 1921 (Box 7, Folder 35)
    - M.A. Thesis - Columbia (Box 7, Folder 36)
    - Poetry, Prose, 1920's (Box 7, Folder 37)
    - Leslie Severinghaus Collection of Prose, 1925-27 (Box 7, Folder 38)
    - Leslie Severinghaus Poetry, Prose, 1930's (Box 7, Folder 39)
    - The Rise and Demise of an Aspiring Poet, 1989 (Box 7, Folder 40)
    - `"More Written Material from the China Period", 1922-27 (Box 7, Folder 41)
    - Leslie Severinghaus - Peking Journal Transcription, 1923-27 (Box 7, Folder 42)
    - Leslie Severinghaus - Handbook/Planner - PUMC, 1927 (Box 7, Folder 43)
    - Fragment - Leslie Severinghaus - Peking Memoirs, p. 331-414 (Box 7, Folder 44)
    - Leslie Severinghaus Peking Memoirs (Box 7, Folder 45)
    - Leslie Severinghaus Peking Recollections (Box 7, Folder 46)
    - Leslie Severinghaus account of trip to Wheeling, West Virginia with Sheldon and Aura, 1941 (Box 7, Folder 47)
    - Bear Trapping and Gaspé Trip, 1958 (Box 7, Folder 48)
    - Newfoundland Diary, 1959 (Box 7, Folder 49)
    - Leslie Severinghaus - Journal Entry, March 19-28, 1965 (Box 7, Folder 50)
    - Journal Entries - Feb. 28-June 15, 1970 (Box 7, Folder 51)
    - Leslie Severinghaus - Reminisce, 1994 (Box 7, Folder 52)
    - Travel Diary - Tokyo (Box 7, Folder 53)
    - Wheeling High School - Reunions (Box 7, Folder 54)
    - Leslie Severinghaus-Emmavail Severinghaus Childhood Storybook List (Box 7, Folder 55)
    - List of books in Luce-Severinghaus collection (Box 7, Folder 56)
    - "Parallel Narration of Luce Family and Severinghaus Family (Box 7, Folder 57)
    - Leslie Severinghaus-Emmavail Severinghaus Wedding Anecdote (Box 7, Folder 58)
    - Memoirs fragment, Peking Period p. 223-307 (Box 7, Folder 59)
    - Untitled Memoirs fragments, Peking (Box 7, Folder 60)
    - Family and Visitors log, 1978 (Box 7, Folder 61)
    - Thanksgiving scrapbook (photocopy) 65 year celebration, 19987 (Box 7, Folder 62)
    - Introduction to Discovery (original) (Box 7, Folder 63)
    - Scrapbook pages (photocopy), 1920's (Box 7, Folder 64)
    - Memoir fragments (Box 7, Folder 65)
    - Journal fragments (Box 7, Folder 66)
    - Christmas tree ornament: Republican Presidential Task Force, 1985 (Box 8, Folder 1)
    - Terre Haute High School commencement, 1884 (Box 8, Folder 2)
    - "The Daily Altar," inscribed "To Willard with love from John Dec. 25, '09", 1907 (Box 8, Folder 3)
    - Esther Severinghaus five year record book, 1918 (Box 8, Folder 4)
    - Address book with jottings and verses - ? Severinghaus (Box 8, Folder 5)
    - Photos of Emmavail Severinghaus art work, 1910-13 (Box 8, Folder 6)
    - The Visitor; or Calls of Usefulness inscribed A. E. Nay, 1855 (Box 8, Folder 7)
    - Leslie Severinghaus - monthly expense books, 1927 (Box 8, Folder 8)
    - Sara M. Nay and Aura E. Severinghaus Passports, 1922-23 (Box 8, Folder 9)
    - Autograph album of Bena W. Schneider, Boonville, Ind. (Box 8, Folder 10)
    - Dancing invitation (Box 8, Folder 11)
    - J. F. Severinghaus clippings notebook (Box 8, Folder 12)
    - brochure: "Evening Pastimes", 1897 (Box 8, Folder 13)
    - Ida Mock's (?) Autograph album, 1883 (Box 8, Folder 14)
    - "The Student's Composition Book" (Box 8, Folder 15)
    - Leslie Severinghaus automobile expense/travel log, 1960? (Box 8, Folder 16)
    - Very early Root Family documents (with photographs) (Box 9, Folder 1)
    - Leslie Severinghaus diary (original), 1923 (Box 9, Folder 2)
    - Journal of family occurrences (from correspondence), 1930's,-40's (Box 9, Folder 3)
    - "Reminiscences of Isabel Ingram Mayer based on her diary kept 1922-24, Peking, China" (Box 9, Folder 4)
    - "Tea for Two: The Anatomy of an American Friendship", 1922 (Box 9, Folder 5)
    - Aura E. Severinghaus - assorted correspondence (oversize folder, see Aura E. Severinghaus, assorted correspondence, letter sized for more) (Box 9, Folder 6)
    - Elizabeth Root Luce -- notes/writing (Box 9, Folder 7)